(お岩)は～い おめでとう！
All right. Congratulations. You've passed the job interview.
(お岩)面接合格！
(銀時)えっ…!?
["Briefs Will Unavoidably Get Skidmarks"]
(お岩)40秒で支度しな！
You have 40 seconds to get ready!
ｸﾞｽﾞは嫌いだよ！
こっちも忙しいんだからね！
I hate dawdlers! I'm busy, too, you know!
えっ…？ 何これ 何なの？
What? What is this?
お登勢のﾔﾂ
なかなか ｲｷのいいのを➡
Looks like Otose has sent over someone quite spirited.
よこしてくれたじゃないか｡
はい？
Huh?
女どもは てんでﾀﾞﾒだが
あのﾒｶﾞﾈの小僧は惜しかったね｡
Those girls weren't any good, but the kid with the glasses wasn't too bad.
霊視まではよかったが➡
He could see spirits, but you can't handle this job if you're susceptible to spiritual possession.
とり憑かれるようでは
この仕事は やってけない｡
いや 何を言ってんだよ 仕事って｡
What job are you talking about?
(ﾚｲ)女将 団体様 ご到着だよ｡
うわ～っ！
Okami, a group has arrived.
ﾚｲ 新入りのｷﾞﾝだ｡
ここのｲﾛﾊを叩きこんでやんな｡
Rei, this is Gin, the new guy. Pound the basics into him.
ｷﾞﾝ ここでは本名を語るな｡
Gin, don't use your real name here.
名とは 魂と肉体をつなぐ鎖｡
Your name is the chain that links you to your body.
ﾔﾂらに知られれば あっちの
世界に引きずり込まれるよ｡
If they find out your name, you'll be dragged to the other world.
いや もう すでに 変な世界に
引きずり込まれてるんだけど｡
I've already been dragged into a strange world.
何これ？ もう 別のｱﾆﾒじゃね？
What is this? A different anime?
(お岩)それから
こいつを持っていきな｡
Take this too. As long as you have this, most spirits will listen to you.
[Persimmons and Peanuts]
そいつがあれば
大概の霊は言うことをきく｡
やりすぎるんじゃないよ！
Don't overfeed them! If you understand, then go. I hate dawdlers!
わかったら さっさと行きな｡
ｸﾞｽﾞは嫌いだよ！
行くよ ｷﾞﾝ こっちだ｡
Let's go, Gin. This way.
普通に話しかけんな！
なんだ お前！
Don't talk to me so casually! What are you?!
ﾚｲだ｡ 足 引っ張んじゃないよ｡
I'm Rei. Don't get in my way.
ﾚｲとか そんなん言うな！
ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞだ！ ああっ！
Don't talk about spirits. You're a Stand!
ｱﾝﾀ そんなんで
ﾎﾝﾄに大丈夫なの？
Can you really handle this?
これから 霊… ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞ相手に➡
We're going to have to do business with spirits...I mean, Stands.
商売しなきゃいけないってのに｡
ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞ相手… どういうことだよ？
With Stands? What do you mean?
だって ｱﾝﾀ 女将の友人が➡
You were sent here by the Okami's friend to work at this inn, right?
この旅館で働かせるために
よこした人なんでしょ｡
ばばあが!?
そうよ｡
The old hag?
Yes.
でも ここで働くには
特殊な能力が必要だから➡
But you need special abilities to work here, so Mrs. Oiwa was testing your aptitude.
お岩さんが ｱﾝﾀたちの
適性を試していたの｡
幽霊… ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞたちが
湯治にやってくる➡
Ghost...Stands come here for the hot springs.
このｽﾀﾝﾄﾞ温泉で
やっていけるかどうか｡
She was testing to see whether you could handle working at this Stand hot spring.
ｷﾞﾝ… ｱﾝﾀは選ばれたのよ｡
Gin...you were chosen.
A s-s-s-s-s-Stand hot-spring?!
ｽ… ｽｽｽ ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞ温泉!?
そう ここは 磁気が強く
ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞが具現化しやすい｡
Yes.
This area is strongly magnetized, making it easy for Stands to materialize themselves.
ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞが集まりやすい
霊界ｽﾎﾟｯﾄってやつなんだ｡
It's what you would call a spiritual hot spot where Stands would all gather around.
《あ… あのばばあ！
That old hag!
温泉いってこいなんて
おかしいと思ったら➡
I thought that it was strange for her to let us go to a hot spring. She sold me out!
ｵﾚを身売りしやがったぁ！
しかも ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞ温泉!?》
To a Stand hot spring!
いつもは お岩さんと
私たち数名のｱｼｽﾀﾝﾄで➡
We usually get by with Mrs. Oiwa and several of us assistants,
切り盛りしているんだが➡
この時期は ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞが
たくさん来て忙しくて➡
but around this time, a lot of Stands come and we're busy.
ｱﾝﾀのような
ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞに適性のある人を…｡
We get people like you with an aptitude for Stands.
待てぇ！ ｵﾚが ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞに適性!?
Wait!
I have an aptitude for Stands?!
あるわけねえだろ！
That's impossible!
I almost took a crap three times just talking to you.
すでに今 お前としゃべってて
すでに３回 ｳﾝｺ出そうに…｡
あっ やべえ！ 今もきた！
Oh no. Again!
わかってないわね｡
You don't understand.
私としゃべってる時点で
ｱﾝﾀは適性があるのさ｡
The fact that you're talking to me shows that you have an aptitude.
ｳﾝｺが出そうなのは
ｱﾝﾀが ただのﾍﾀﾚ➡
You just feel like taking a crap because you're a loser--no, you're just crappy.
いや ｳﾝｺﾀﾚなだけよ｡
ふざけんな！ ｵﾚは知らねえ！
No way. I don't care!
ばばあどもに なんで
踊らされなきゃならねえんだ！
Why do I have to be manipulated by those old hags? I'm going home!
ｵﾚは帰る！
どこに？
To where?
山道は 私たちが
岩を落としてふさいだ｡
We closed off the mountain path by dropping a boulder on it.
それに ｱﾝﾀが逃げれば…｡
And besides, if you run away...
(新八)我が輩が UNOである｡
(みんな)ﾌﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
I myself have "UNO."
(ﾚｲ)ｱﾝﾀの仲間たちは
永遠に閣下として➡
Your friends will have to play UNO forever as "His Excellency."
UNOをし続けることになるわよ｡
ﾃ… ﾃﾒｴら！
(幽霊)ﾚｲ！
Y-You bastards!
Rei, could you help me for a moment?
ちょっと手伝ってくれないか｡
うわ～！ 新手か！
Another one!
Get used to it already.
いい加減 慣れなよ ｱﾝﾀ｡
(幽霊)早く ﾚｲ！
Quickly, Rei, that customer is at it again.
あのお客さんが また…｡
(ﾚｲ)ｷﾞﾝ 出番だよ｡
Gin, take care of it.
あん…!?
あっ！ な… 何だよ あれ!?
What is that? Who is that Stand?
誰だよ あのｽﾀﾝﾄﾞ！
He's just been hitting that wall. He's creating poltergeists.
ずっと壁 殴ってるよ｡
ずっと ﾎﾟﾙﾀｰｶﾞｲｽﾄ起こしてるよ｡
(信長)ﾏｼﾞ ﾑｶﾂｸわ 光秀｡
I'm so pissed off at Mitsuhide... I really can't believe that it's Mitsuhide.
ﾏｼﾞありえねえんだけど 光秀！
誰だよ 光秀って
何なんだよ あの酔っ払い！
Who is Mitsuhide? Who is that drunk?
信長｡
信長!? あれ 織田 信長なの!?
Nobunaga.
Nobunaga?! That's Nobunaga Oda?!
なんで信長 ﾌﾞﾘｰﾌ一丁なんだよ！
しかも ﾀﾞﾙﾀﾞﾙじゃねえか！
Why is he only wearing briefs?! They're hanging loose on him, too.
(ﾚｲ)西洋かぶれだから｡
He likes to adopt western mannerisms.
Why does he have to wear briefs of all things?!
なんで よりによって
ﾌﾞﾘｰﾌﾁｮｲｽなんだよ｡
西洋いろいろあるよ！
もっといいの いっぱいあるよ！
There are lots of other types of western clothes he can wear.
There are a lot better things.
ﾏｼﾞありえねえ！ 普通あそこで
裏切りとかなくねえ？
I mean come on, seriously.
Most people wouldn't betray me there.
天下統一 一歩手前だよ？
空気 読めよ！
It was right before I took control of the whole country that I grasp the situation.
おい もう完全に本能寺のこと
引きずってるよ｡
Hey, he's totally dwelling on what happened at Honnoji Temple.
ここ来ると毎回ああなのよ｡
ｷﾞﾝ ｱﾝﾀがなんとかしなさい｡
It happens every time he comes here. Gin, do something about it.
What can I do about that drunk?
どうしろってんだよ
あんな酔っ払い！
いいから｡ 年寄りは若者と
しゃべれれば それで満足なのよ｡
Just do something! Old people like talking to young people.
ｵﾒｴがいけばいいだろうが！
(物音)
You should do it.
おい 隣の部屋からも
何か聞こえてくるぞ！
Hey, I hear something coming from the room next door, too.
何よ これ？
What is this?
おい また壁 殴ってるﾔﾂいるぞ｡
Hey, there's someone else pounding on the walls.
何なんだよ おい
流行ってんの？ あれ｡
What's going on? Is it some sort of fad?
誰だよ あれ
いいかげんにしろよ！
Who is that? Cut it out.
(光秀)
もうさ あの魔王 信長をさ➡
I mean, come on... I took down that demon Nobunaga, so let's end it there!
とったわけだからさ
いいじゃん それで終わりで｡
ｵﾚでいいじゃんよ ﾄｯﾌﾟ！
It's all right for me to be at the top, right?
それをなんか後から
ｺﾞﾁｬｺﾞﾁｬ ｺﾞﾁｬｺﾞﾁｬ➡
But nooo, he just had to start making a huge fuss about it... that damn Hideyoshi.
ﾏｼﾞ ﾑｶﾂｸんですけど 秀吉！
光秀じゃねえ？
あれ完全に 明智 光秀じゃねえ!?
It's Mitsuhide! That's definitely Mitsuhide Akechi!
まずいだろ これ！
This is bad, isn't it?! Two guys who shouldn't meet are in neighboring rooms.
絶対 会ってはならねえﾔﾂらが
部屋 隣り合わせじゃん！
部屋割り考えろよ！
っつうか なんで ｺｲﾂもﾌﾞﾘｰﾌ!?
Think about where you put people!
And why is he in briefs, too?!
(ﾚｲ)信長の部下だから
合わせたのよ｡
He was Nobunaga's subordinate so he was going along.
さすがに光秀は ぴっちりﾌﾞﾘｰﾌ
きれいね｡
Naturally, Mitsuhide has tight briefs. They're clean.
Now's not the time to be talking about that!
言ってる場合じゃねえんだよ！
Something terrible will happen if they meet.
ｱｲﾂら 鉢合わせしたら
えらいことに…｡
(物音)
あれ？ 何か また隣から…｡
Huh? I hear something coming from the next room.
まただよ
あぁ これもう やべえよ｡
Again?! Oh, this is really bad. It's got to be him.
絶対 ｱｲﾂじゃん！
これ もう絶対に秀…｡
He's got to be Hideyoshi.
I'm going to kill that barber.
(ｻﾞﾋﾞｴﾙ)ぶっ殺す！ ﾊﾞｰﾊﾞｰ！
Who is he?!
誰だ これ!?
｢ぶっ殺す ﾊﾞｰﾊﾞｰ｣って何だよ？
And who's this barber he wants to kill?
ここ秀吉だろ？ どう考えても
秀吉が信長の悪口 言いながら➡
Hideyoshi has to be here!
No matter how I think of it,
this is the time when Hideyoshi has to come out and badmouth Nobunaga!
出てくるところだろ｡
三すくみだろ！
A three-way standoff should form!
あれ ｻﾞﾋﾞｴﾙさんだわ｡
ｷﾘｽﾄ教 伝来した人｡
That's Xavier.
He's the person who introduced Christianity to Japan.
でも 髪型は流行らなかったの｡
流行るか！
But his hair style was never popular.
How could it be?!
どんだけ しようもない理由で
この世に残ってんだよ！
For what kind of pathetic reason is he staying here?!
っつうか ﾊﾞｰﾊﾞｰのせいにすんな！
Don't blame things on your barber!
(秀吉)あの すみません｡
あっ！
Umm, excuse me.
Umm, I'm the person staying across from your room.
あの…
向かいの部屋の者なんすけど➡
ﾊﾞﾝﾊﾞﾝ ﾊﾞﾝﾊﾞﾝうるさいんすけど｡
But your thumping is really noisy.
寝れないんすけど
静かにしてもらえません？
I can't sleep. Could you please keep it quiet?
お… おい あれ
ひょっとして秀吉じゃねえか？
Ah! He's Hideyoshi, isn't he?
それにしても 信長ﾑｶﾂｸわ～｡
And anyway, Nobunaga is really annoying.
猿とか呼んでんじゃねえよ｡
ﾏｼﾞでﾃﾒｴも ﾅﾏｽﾞ面だろうがよ｡
Don't call me a monkey. You look like a catfish you know.
(ﾚｲ)本当だわ よく わかったわね｡
You're right! How did you know?
だって ﾊﾟﾝﾂ汚ねえもん
ｳﾝｺついてるもん｡
That's because his underwear is dirty! It has crap on it!
秀吉 ﾒｯﾁｬついてそうだもん｡
うん！
Hideyoshi seems like he'd have a lot on them!
Yeah!
あっ！ つうか
分析してる場合じゃねえ！
Now's not the time to be analyzing this--! If the Brief Trio meet...
このままじゃ
ﾌﾞﾘｰﾌ３が鉢合わせ…！
ああ～っ！
(信長)あれ？ 久しぶりじゃん
来てたんだ お前らも｡
Huh? It's been a while. You two came, too?
Yeah. I haven't seen you in a while.
(光秀)
あぁ どうも ごぶさたしてます｡
(秀吉)ﾎﾝﾄですね
どれくらいぶりでしたっけ？
That's true. How long has it been?
あら 意外に普通だわ｡
いや｡
Oh, they're acting unexpectedly normal.
Yep...
光秀 ｵﾚらは あれだよね
最後に会ったの 本能寺だっけ？
Mitsuhide, the last time we met was Honnoji Temple, right?
あ… そうでしたかね？
Really?
あんま覚えてないっすね ﾎﾞｸ｡
I don't really remember.
やべえよ
いきなり突っ込んでるよ 信長！
This is bad. Nobunaga is jumping into matters.
いや 覚えてないっていうか
あれじゃん！
You don't remember? That thing happened?
えっ 覚えてないの？ ﾏｼﾞで｡
覚えてないっすね｡
What? You really don't remember?
I don't remember. I was immediately killed afterwards by Sir Hideyoshi.
あのあと すぐ殺されたんで
ﾎﾞｸも 秀吉殿に｡
あぁ そうなんすか
ｵﾚ やったんだ｡
Oh, really? I did that? I don't remember either.
いや ｵﾚも覚えてないっすね｡
つうか 光秀さん
あのあとって言ってる時点で➡
Besides, Mitsuhide, the fact that you said "afterwards" means that you do remember
覚えてるじゃないすか 本能寺｡
Honnoji Temple.
いや あのあとって あれだよ｡
By "afterwards" I meant that thing. I meant after you told me to attack Mohri.
殿に 毛利 攻めろ って
言われたあとだよ｡
そこから記憶があやふや…
うん｡
My memory is vague after that.
おい 何なんだよ
このｸﾞﾀﾞｸﾞﾀﾞの会話｡
Hey, what's with this lousy conversation?
いや 光秀さん
ﾎﾞｸも殺されたって言ったじゃん｡
But Mr. Mitsuhide, you said that you were also killed.
それって 信長も殺されたって
知ってるってことじゃん｡
That means that you knew that Nobunaga was killed.
つうか ぶっちゃけ殺したじゃん
ｵﾚ 知ってるもん｡
Anyway, you totally killed him. I know you did.
ちょ… ちょっと待って 猿｡
えっ？ 今 お前➡
Hold on one second, Monkey.
What? Did you just refer to me as just plain Nobunaga?
信長って
呼び捨てにしなかった？
言ったね いつも悪口言ってるから
つい 言っちゃったね｡
He did. He's always badmouthing him and it slipped out.
言ったっすね え？ ﾀﾞﾒっすか？
I did, didn't I? Huh? Is there anything wrong with that?
開き直ってるよ
なんか ｺｲﾂ ﾑｶﾂｸな｡
He's lashing back. He's pretty annoying.
あの 殿は死んだから
知らないでしょうけど➡
My lord, you died, so you may not know this, but I did take control of the whole nation.
ｵﾚ 一応 天下とったんで｡
まぁ そういう感じなんで
猿とかいうのは➡
That's what happened, so don't call me a monkey, you know?
ちょっと もう 勘弁みたいな｡
へぇ～ 天下とったんだ
すげぇじゃん 猿のくせに｡
Oh? You took control of the nation. That's pretty impressive...for a monkey.
あれ？
ちょっと 今 ｶﾁﾝときたな｡
Huh? I'm kind of offended by that. There's no problem in me doing that.
え？ べつに
ｵﾚ やってもいいっすよ｡
(光秀)天下とったといっても
所詮 ｵﾚの横取りですもんね｡
You only took control of the country because you snatched it away from me.
あん？ いや 横取ったの
お前じゃねえ？
You're the one who snatched it away, weren't you?
つうか 基本 お前ら
ｵﾚいなかったら 成立してないし｡
Besides, it wouldn't have been possible without me.
あぁ!? やんのか ｺﾗ！
こいよ ｺﾗ！
You want to fight?
Bring it on. I can take you down in one hit.
お前なんか 一発だ ｺﾗ！
(光秀)つうか お前
すでに ｵﾚに殺されてるし｡
Anyway, I've already killed you.
いや お前は ｵﾚに殺されてるし｡
But I killed you.
あぁ もう そこまで そこまで！
ちょっと落ち着いて｡
All right, stop right there. Hold on! Calm down.
(銃声)
いらっしゃいませ｡
Come in.
(銀時たち)ようこそ 仙望郷へ｡
Welcome to Senbokyo.
(幽霊)いやぁ 今年も
成仏できずに来ちゃったよ｡
I came again. I couldn't pass on this year as well.
ささ どうぞ こちらへ｡
Right this way.
ｷﾞﾝ お客様のお荷物を
お持ちして｡
Gin, carry the guest's bags.
えっ!? あ はい｡
(幽霊)あぁ すみません｡
Huh?! Oh, okay.
Thank you. Here.
じゃあ これ｡
(幽霊)いやぁ
この温泉に入らないと➡
The year is a waste if I don't get to this hot spring.
なんだか １年 調子が悪くてね｡
ﾎﾝﾄ 生き返るよね 温泉って｡
(ﾚｲ)ｳﾌﾌ お客様ったら｡
Hot springs really bring you back to life.
You're already dead.
(ﾚｲ)もう死んでるでしょ｡
(幽霊)いけねえ そうだった｡
Oh no! That's right.
(ﾚｲ)ﾎﾝﾄ 幽霊ｷﾞｬｸﾞが
お好きな方ですね｡
You really like jokes about ghosts, don't you?
温泉のほうは 24時間
入れるようになっていますから➡
The hot spring is open at all hours of the day. You can go in whenever you like.
お好きなときに
入っていただいて結構ですから｡
(幽霊)いやぁ 早くお湯に浸かって
手足を伸ばしたいよ｡
I can't wait to stretch out my arms and legs in the hot water.
(ﾚｲ)ｳﾌﾌ お客様ったら
足なんて もうないでしょ｡
*
(幽霊)
あっ いけねえ そうだった｡
Oh no! That's right.
(ﾚｲ)ﾎﾝﾄ 幽霊ｷﾞｬｸﾞが
お好きな方ですね｡
You really like jokes about ghosts, don't you?
それじゃあ お部屋のほう
こちらになりますんで➡
This is your room. Enjoy your stay.
ごゆっくり｡
あら？ ｷﾞﾝ 何やってるの？
Oh? Gin--?! What are you doing? Bring the guest's bags right now.
早くお客様のお荷物｡
あぁ すみません
お荷物 お返しします｡
Oh, sorry. Here are your bags. Please enjoy your stay.
じゃあ ごゆっくりと
おくつろぎくださいませ｡
なんか違くね？
This isn't mine, is it?
(幽霊)おい そこのｷﾐ｡
あっ はいはい はいは～い｡
Hey, you there!
Yes, yes, yes, yes...
ちょっと 体 洗うの
手伝ってもらえないかね｡
Could you help me wash myself?
はい ただいま あ…｡
All right. Right away.
背中が かゆくてね｡
My back is so itchy.
あの… すみません｡
Umm, excuse me, but where is your back?
背中って
どこに ありましたっけ？
何を言ってるんだ
背中は背中だろ｡
What are you talking about? My back is my back.
そうっすよね｡
背中は背中ですよね｡
Yes. Your back is your back, isn't it?
え～っと…｡
あれ？
なんか 変な音しなかったかね？
Huh? Did you hear something strange?
してません｡
全然 何もしてません｡
Not at all. I haven't done anything.
あっ！ あれかな？
Oh! Do you suppose it could be that thing?
I might have hummed a little jazz tune!
ちょっと 今 小粋なｼﾞｬｽﾞを
口ずさんでしまったかも…｡
Oh? You like jazz?
ほう… ｷﾐはｼﾞｬｽﾞをたしなむのかね｡
なかなか いい趣味をしている｡
You've got good taste.
Anyway, get the upper right a little.
それより もうちょっと右上を…｡
Upper right?! What part is the upper right?!
右上!? 右上って どこから右上!?
ﾌﾌ… ｷﾐ ﾄﾞﾗﾑを想像したまえ｡
ｼﾝﾊﾞﾙだ｡ ｼﾝﾊﾞﾙを叩きたまえ｡
Son, imagine a drum set.
Imagine you're hitting the cymbols.
《知らねえよ ｼﾞｬｽﾞなんて！》
I don't know Jazz.
こ… このへんか？
失敬だな ｷﾐ！
Is it this area?
How rude! What are you touching? That's my "C"...
どこを触ってるんだ？ ｷﾐは！
そこは ｷﾐ… ﾁ…｡
Huh? Huh? What? Huh? "C?!" It's on the side of your face!
えっ!? えっ!? 何？ えっ!? ﾁ!?
顔の横っすよ！
なんで 顔の横に ﾁ…!?
Why would you have a "C" on the side of your face?
とんだ じゃじゃ馬奏者だ！
You're quite the wild performer.
You looked like you were going for the cymbals, but you went for the "C" instead.
まさか ｼﾝﾊﾞﾙにくると見せて ﾁ…｡
こんな即興ﾗｲﾌﾞ 見たことがない｡
I've never seen such an extempore performance.
私は 部屋に帰るとしよう｡
I'm going back to my room. I want to put this feeling to music.
この感動を譜面に残しておきたい｡
ちょっと待ってください！
Wait a second!
体が あれなんで！
体が ｼﾞｬｽﾞってるんで！
Your body's all like this! It's jazzed up.
あぁ ｼﾞｬｽﾞっているともさ｡ だから
今のうちに書き留めておきたい｡
Yes. It's jazzed up. That's why I want to write it down.
ちょ… ちょ… 待…！
Hold on! Hold on!
(お岩)私の見込み違いだったかね｡
客から ｸﾚｰﾑが殺到してるよ｡
It looks like you weren't what I expected you would be like.
Complaints have been pouring in. How will you clear this up, Gin?
どう 落とし前
つけてくれるんだい？ ｷﾞﾝ｡
いや いや… ｵﾚ
結構 がんばったほうだと思うよ｡
Well, I think I tried pretty hard. I don't like Stands, but I even washed their backs.
ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞ 苦手だってのにさ｡
その背中を
洗い流すまでになったんだよ｡
もう そろそろ 帰して…｡
(TAGOSAKU)甘ったれてんじゃねえ｡
Let me go already.
Don't be such a spoiled brat!
When you work, you're judged by your results!
仕事はな 結果 出して
初めて 評価されるんだよ！
がんばったって
結果がついてこなけりゃ➡
If your hard work doesn't produce any results, there's no point, you good-for-nothing!
なんの意味もねえ！
このごく潰しが!!
な… なんだ!? ﾃﾒｴ！ ｺﾗ!!
Who the hell do you think you are, talking so big to me, you Peanut Bastard!
偉そうな口 叩きやがって
ﾋﾟｰﾅｯﾂ野郎！ もう ﾋﾞﾋﾞんねえぞ｡
I'm not scared anymore!
こっちも いろいろ やって
ちったぁ ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞは慣れたんだよ｡
After working here, I've gotten used to Stands. I'm not afraid of you anymore.
ﾃﾒｴなんか もう 怖…｡
ｱｳ ｱｳ ｱｳ ｱｳ ｱｳ…！
なんか 調子 のって
すみませんでした！
I'm sorry for getting carried away!
そのへんにしておやりな ｱﾝﾀ｡
Just leave it at that, dear. We need the help. He's better than nothing.
人手は いくらあっても
足りないんだ｡
あんなもんでも
いないよりは ﾏｼだよ｡
もう 接客はいいよ ｷﾞﾝ｡
裏方に回って 雑用でもやってな｡
You don't have to deal with guests anymore, Gin.
Go to the back and do some routine chores.
(お岩)明日は上客
かの東照大権現 徳川 家康公が➡
We have an important guest tomorrow.
The Light of the East, the former Great Gongen,
Prince Ieyasu Tokugawa, is coming to our hot spring.
湯治においでになる日｡
お前のような者に 前に出られては
この温泉の評価が落ちる｡
The rating of this hot spring will drop if someone like you were to appear before him.
You stay quiet.
おとなしくしておくんだよ｡
(新八たち)ﾌﾊﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
我が輩が UNOである｡
(神楽)ﾌﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
I have "UNO."
甘いな｡ 我が輩は ﾄﾞﾛｰ４である｡
(お妙)我が輩も ﾄﾞﾛｰ４である｡
Not good enough. I have a "draw four."
I also have a "draw four."
ﾌﾊﾊﾊﾊ！ ｷｻﾏら
そんな隠し手があったとは｡
I never expected you to have such a trick up your sleeve.
(新八たち)ﾌﾊﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
《なんで… なんで ｵﾚばっか➡
Why?
Why must this happen to me? Did I do something wrong?!
こんな目に
遭わなきゃならねえんだよ！
ｵﾚ なんか悪いことしたか？
わけのわからん ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞ旅館で
急に働かされて➡
I'm forced to work in some inn for Stands, I'm told I'm useless,
使えねえと ののしられ➡
and I'm tired, but I can't sleep because of them playing UNO every single night.
疲れてんのに
毎晩 毎晩 UNOで眠れねえし｡
おまけに 主食が柿ﾋﾟｰ｡
この仕打ち…｡
If that weren't bad enough, I've been living on Kaki-pea.
This treatment...
もう ｶﾞﾏﾝならねえ｡
もう 黙っちゃいられねえ｡
I can't take it anymore. I can't stay quiet.
やってやる！
閣下もｸｿも もはや 関係ねえ!!
I'm going to do it. "His Excellency" and crap don't matter anymore.
この温泉旅館
ｵﾚの手でぶっ潰す！》
I'm going to crush this hot spring inn!
(ﾚｲ)その目だよ｡
That look.
その目を待ってた｡
ﾚｲ！
I've been waiting for that look.
Rei...
(ﾚｲ)初めて会ったときから➡
When we first met,
ｱﾝﾀは この温泉旅館に
革命を起こす男だと信じていたよ｡
I knew that you were the man who would start a revolution at this hot spring inn.
私も少ない賃金で
ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞを馬車馬のごとく こき使い➡
We Stands are worked off like a horse for small wages while the Okami gets rich.
私腹を肥やす女将のやり方には
もうｳﾝｻﾞﾘでね｡
I'm sick of doing things her way.
ｷﾞﾝ… ｱﾝﾀは 私の見たところ➡
Gin, from what I can see,
you have the potential of a Stand user to rivals that of the Okami.
女将に匹敵する
ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞ使いの素質を持っている｡
私が ｱﾝﾀのｽﾀﾝﾄﾞになってあげる｡
I'll become your Stand. So let's start a revolution at this hot spring inn.
だから 一緒に この温泉旅館に
革命を起こそうじゃないのさ｡
《勝てるのか？
あの女将のｽﾀﾝﾄﾞに…》
Can we win against the Okami's Stand?
(ﾚｲ)仙望郷 最強のｽﾀﾝﾄﾞ ﾀｺﾞｻｸ｡
10年前 他界した女将の旦那だ｡
Tagosaku is the strongest Stand in Senbokyo.
He's the Okami's husband who passed away ten years ago.
他界したあとも
女将とﾀｯｸﾞを組み➡
Even after he passed away, he formed a team with the Okami and they've controlled Senbokyo.
仙望郷を牛耳ってる｡
The ordinary Stands and I can't take them on even if we grouped together.
まず私は もちろん 並のｽﾀﾝﾄﾞじゃ
束になっても かなわない｡
だが 悪霊には悪霊をさ｡
But we need evil spirits to fight evil spirits.
ﾌｯ…｡
目覚めよ！
歴史に名を刻む英霊たちよ｡
Awaken.
Heroic spirits who have left their mark on history...
目覚めし刻が来たのだ！
Now is the time to awaken.
Turn your desire for revenge into a blade and rise up now.
復讐心を刃に変えて
今こそ立ち上がれ！
ﾌﾞﾘｰﾌ３よ！
Brief Trio.
おはようさん｡ 信長 光秀 秀吉！
Good morning, Nobunaga, Mitsuhide, and Hideyoshi.
(３人)あん？ 誰だ ｷｻﾏは!?
Who the hell are you?
♪♪～
来やがったな 家康｡
Ieyasu is here.
いいか？ 信長 秀吉 光秀！
Listen, Nobunaga...
Hideyoshi, Mitsuhide...
お前らに やってもらうことは
昨日 言ったとおり！
Do exactly what I told you to do yesterday.
家康に数々の嫌がらせを仕掛け
歓迎ﾑｰﾄﾞをぶち壊すことだ｡
Play a lot of nasty tricks on Ieyasu and ruin his welcome.
そして この宿の評判を地に落とし
この温泉をぶっ潰す！
The rating of this inn will crash into the ground and the inn will be destroyed.
You got that?
そのへんは
理解したな お前ら！
Hey, are you listening? Hey!
おい！
聞いてんのか お前ら!? おい！
あぁ やんのか!?
You want to fight?
What did you say?
(秀吉)なんじゃ!?
あとで厠 来いや！
Come to the bathrooms later.
Let's do it right now.
今 やったらぁ！
ここで やったらぁ！
Right here.
おい～！ もうｹﾝｶすんなって
言ってるだろうが!!
Hey! I told you not to fight anymore!
ほら！ ﾋﾟｰﾅｯﾂやるから｡
(３人)ﾋｬｯﾎｰ！
Come on. I'll give you some peanuts.
まぁ お互い過去に➡
I know that a lot happened in your pasts,
いろいろあったのは
わかるけども➡
but you can't move forward if you keep looking back.
後ろばっか振り向いてたら
前に進めないよ！
今日は もう いったん忘れよう｡
Forget everything for today.
Let's forget all about Honnoji Temple.
本能寺も 全部忘れて
家康だけ見ていこう！
Just focus on Ieyasu.
ｱｲﾂ お前ら いねえ間に
天下とったんだよ！
He took control of the nation after you guys weren't around,
even though he was the least remarkable of any of you.
いちばん ﾊﾟｯとしねえくせに！
(３人)ん？
お前らの本当の敵は家康だ！
なあ！ よし！
Your true enemy is Ieyasu! Okay?!
All right! Then let's do this. Let's all apologize to each other.
じゃあ あれだ！
みんな１回 謝っておこうか！
ﾁｬﾗにしようか！ なあ！
Let's call it all even. Okay?
Come on. Okay?
ほら！ なあ！
殿… あんときは裏切って
すみませんでした！
My lord...I'm sorry for betraying you.
ｴﾗｲ！ 光秀 ｴﾗｲ！
最初に謝るﾔﾂが いちばんｴﾗｲ！
That's good! Good job, Mitsuhide!
The one who apologized first is the most admirable!
信長も許してやろうな！
And you forgive them, Nobunaga.
べ… 別に いいけど
あんまり気にしてないし…｡
It's all right. It didn't really bother me.
ｴﾗｲ！ 信長もｴﾗｲ！
That's good! You did well, too, Nobunaga!
It's pretty hard to forgive the person who killed you.
なかなか できないよ！
自分 殺した相手許すなんて！
おい 何やってんだ 秀吉｡
Hey, what are you doing, Hideyoshi?
早く光秀に謝れよ ﾃﾒｴよ！
Hurry up and apologize to Mitsuhide!
(秀吉)ｲﾔっすね｡
ｵﾚ 別に悪いことしてないんで｡
I don't want to. I didn't do anything wrong.
ｵﾚは 殿の仇である明智殿を
殺しただけなんで｡
I just killed Sir Akechi to avenge my lord.
なに ｺｲﾂ 超うぜぇんだけど｡
空気読めよ ﾃﾒｴよ｡
What's wrong with this guy? He's really annoying.
Grasp the situation. You even have crap on your underwear!
ﾊﾟﾝﾂに ｳﾝｺついてるくせによ！
じゃあ いいわ｡
ｵﾚも さっき許したの➡
Fine. Then I take back my forgiveness.
なしってことで｡
Look at that, Hideyoshi!  This is your fault.
ほ～ら みろよ 秀吉よ！
ﾃﾒｴのせいだぞ！
You even have skidmarks on your underwear.
ﾊﾟﾝﾂに ｳﾝｺついてるくせによ！
いや だって… じゃあ 殿も
ｵﾚに謝ってくださいよ｡
I don't want to.
Then apologize to me for calling me a monkey.
猿とか言ったの｡
(信長)猿に猿って言って➡
What's wrong with calling a monkey a monkey, Monkey?
何が悪ぃんだよ 猿！
あぁ 信長！ 手出したらいかん!!
Aw, Nobunaga, you mustn't lay hands on him. Or your feet.
足もだ！ もうやめろって
言ってんだろうが!!
I told you to stop.
Here. Some peanuts.
ほら ﾋﾟｰﾅｯﾂ！
(３人)ｳｯｷｰ！
仲直りするのは 難しそうね｡
It looks like it'll be difficult for them to make up.
Oh well. They'll come around.
しかたねえ｡
まぁ なるようになるだろ｡
とりあえず 風呂場を張るぞ！
風呂場であれば➡
Anyway, keep watch over the bath.
Everyone becomes defenseless in the bath.
誰もが無防備になるのは
間違いない｡
(光秀)奇襲作戦か｡
本能寺を思い出すな｡
A surprise attack, huh? It reminds me of Honnoji Temple.
(信長)いや 桶狭間だろ!?
No, Okehazama.
Anyway, you really aren't sorry, are you? "It reminds me of Honnoji Temple". I don't want to remember that.
つうか お前｡
やっぱ 反省してねえだろ!?
何が ｢本能寺を思い出す｣だよ｡
こっちは
思い出したくもねえんだよ！
Shh... Be quiet!
ｼｰｯ 静かにしろ！
あっ おい 誰か来たぞ｡
Hey, someone's come.
家康だ｡
ｱﾚ 家康だよ 間違いねえよ｡
It's Ieyasu! That's Ieyasu. There's no mistake.
見ろよ さすが天下とったﾔﾂは
ﾊﾟﾝﾂも違うぜ｡
Look at that.
As expected, the underwear of the guy who took control of the nation is really something else.
ﾎﾞｸｻｰﾊﾟﾝﾂだ！
ﾜﾝﾗﾝｸ上の ｵｼｬﾚﾊﾟﾝﾂだ！
He's wearing boxers. His underwear is one grade higher than yours, fashion-wise!
その点
やっぱ お前らは汚ねえもん｡
On that note, your underwear is dirty. It's no wonder you couldn't control the nation.
そりゃ 天下とれねえはずだわ～｡
ｵﾚは 天下とりましたよ｡
I took control of the nation.
お前に とれるもんなんて
何もねえよ！
There's nothing for you to take.
天下とる前に
ｹﾂのｳﾝｺとってこいよ ﾊﾞｶ！
Clean the crap off of your butt before you take control of the nation, stupid.
ｷﾞﾝ 行ったわよ どうするの？
Gin, there he goes. What should we do?
秀吉｡
はい｡
Hideyoshi.
Yes?
Switch your crappy underwear with the boxers that Ieyasu took off.
あの家康の脱いだﾎﾞｸｻｰﾊﾟﾝﾂと
お前のｸｿﾊﾟﾝﾂ 取り替えてこい！
ﾏｼﾞっすか ｲﾔっすよ！
あんな ｵｯｻﾝの はいたﾊﾟﾝﾂ！
Are you serious? I don't want the underwear that an old guy like that wore.
お前のﾊﾟﾝﾂ はくﾔﾂの方が
万倍ｲﾔだ！
The guy who'll wear your underwear will hate it ten thousand times more.
(光秀)待ってくださいよ
秀吉殿だけ ｽﾞﾙくないですか!?
Wait. It's not fair for only Hideyoshi to get boxers. I'll go.
ﾎﾞｸｻｰﾊﾟﾝﾂ手に入れて！
ｵﾚが 行きます｡
何してんだよ ﾃﾒｴは！
What are you doing?! We don't need your somewhat clean underwear.
ﾃﾒｴの 中途半端にｷﾚｲなﾊﾟﾝﾂなんざ
いらねえんだよ！
(信長)いや ｵﾚが！
(秀吉)いや ｵﾚだ！
No, I will...
You're fighting over some old guy's underwear. That's gross!
何 ｵｯｻﾝのﾊﾟﾝﾂ取り合ってんだ!?
気持わりいんだよ ﾃﾒｴら！
ｷﾞﾝ 家康が湯船に入ったわ｡
よ～し 突撃しろ！
Gin, Ieyasu has gone into the tub.
All right! Charge. Go fart in the tub.
ﾃﾒｴら 湯船ん中で
思いっきり 屁 こいてこい！
ﾏｼﾞっすか 勘弁してください｡
Are you serious? Give us a break.
せっかく
ｷﾚｲなﾎﾞｸｻｰﾊﾟﾝﾂ手に入れたのに➡
I got some nice boxers. Do I have to get them soiled already?
もう 汚すんですか!?
もう 汚れてるけど｡
They're already soiled.
くっきり ｳﾝ筋ついてるけど！
お前どんだけ汚ねえｹﾂしてんだ!?
There's a streak of crap on it. How dirty is your butt anyway?
あぁ～｡
あぁ どうも いい湯ですねぇ｡
(家康)本当ですねぇ｡
Hello. The water's nice, isn't it?
It sure is.
いいか ｵﾚが ５数えたら
同時にかませ｡
Listen. Do it together when I count to five.
実が出る覚悟で かますんだ｡
いいな!?
Do it with the expectation to bear fruit. Got it?
《５… ４… ３… ２… １…！》
Five...
Four...
Three...
Two...
One.
うぉぉぉ～！
うぅっ…！
《ﾊﾞ… ﾊﾞｶな これは…!?
I-Impossible... This is...
ﾌﾞﾘｰﾌ３ ﾃﾒｴら裏切った…》
Brief Trio, you've double-crossed me...
ぐわっ!!
ｷﾞﾝ！
Gin!
≪ﾚｲ！
Rei, it's not good to have extravagant delusions and swindle men.
誇大な妄想を抱いて
男をたぶらかすものではないぞ｡
惚れた男を
早死にさせたいか｡
Do you want the man you love to die instantly?
(お岩)残念だったな 小僧｡
Too bad, boy.
The Brief Trio have been under my control for quite some time now.
ﾌﾞﾘｰﾌ３も
とうの昔に我が手中にある｡
私を 並のｽﾀﾝﾄﾞ使いと思うなよ｡
Don't think I'm your ordinary Stand user. If you make enemies with me...
私を敵にまわすということは➡
この里
そのものと闘うようなもの｡
You're pretty much fighting this whole village.
私を 倒したくば➡
If you want to defeat me, you need the help of the most powerful Stand.
最強のｽﾀﾝﾄﾞを
味方につけるしかあるまいの｡
まぁ それも ﾑﾘな話｡
But that's impossible.
この 仙望郷に➡
There isn't anyone in Senbokyo who will help you.
お前の味方など
もう １人としていないのだから｡
お前は もう ここで
死ぬまで 私に こき使われて➡
I'm going to have you work here until you die.
生きていくしかないのさ｡
ﾊｰｯ ﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯ…！
《最強のｽﾀﾝﾄﾞ… 最強の仲間…｡
The most powerful Stand. The most powerful ally.
そんなもん…》
Such a person...
≪あれ｡
こんなとこで何やってんすか？
Huh? What are you doing here?
起きてるｱﾙか？
くっさ！
Are you awake?
You stink. What is that smell? A fart?
何ですか このﾆｵｲ ｵﾅﾗ!?
♪♪～
ﾌｯ… 目の前にあらぁ！
They're right before me.
[To be continued]
[Next week, Gintoki...]
[...counterattacks!!]
The next episode: "Gin and His Excellency's Good-for-nothings."
[Gin's requiem reverberates throughout the demonic inn where spirits gather!]
[And finally, a direct confrontation with Tagosaku, the most powerful Stand?!]